CURRICULUM VITAE

A junior full-stack developer, recently graduated from the IT Career Switch software development course. I have extensive experience in Database Management and Application Development. I hold an MSc. in Computer Science, and I am a certified Python Developer (PCAP), with basic Computer Networking skills and knowledge of Linux System Administration. I am a hardworking and proactive person with excellent problem-solving skills and a drive to succeed. I aim to be a valuable addition to your development team.

PERSONAL DETAILS

NAME: Fatimah Sahid

RESIDES: Coventry

TRANSPORT: Public Transport

CONTACT DETAILS: (M) 074671 82783

(E) fatisahid@gmail.com

(W) https://fatisahid.site/myPortfolio/

(GH) https://github.com/FFZahra/fatiSahid/ (please email to request access)

(LI) https://www.linkedin.com/in/fatimah-sahid-9015b21a1/

CODING TRAINEESHIP IT Career Switch Ltd

Coding Traineeship – Full stack developer 1-year program

During the traineeship I had to demonstrate a very competent level of the following programming languages and technical skills

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap 5, jQuery
- PHP, SQL, Remote API access
- Java, Python, C#, Node.js
- Command Line Git, GitHub

I have recently passed my Microsoft 98-383: Introduction to Programming Using HTML and CSS. More information on this certification can be found at: https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/certifications/exams/98-383

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES/METHODOLOGIES: AJAX, MVC, Agile Project Methodology, Linux, Wireframes

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE:

The Full Stack Developer Traineeship included completing 2 real-world projects successfully to specification using a wide range of programming languages. Below are briefs of the two development projects, which can be found in my portfolio website: https://fatisahid.site/myPortfolio

Portfolio Project #1: "Gazetter"

The specification was for a map-based application to provide information on countries – with a focus on a "mobile-first" development, preferably using a framework, and then HTML, CSS and JavaScript with JQuery modules that use AJAX calls, via PHP server-based components, to source data from third-party APIs (Geonames, OpenWeather). The solution was assessed on its delivery to specification, functionality, and usability.

Portfolio Project #2: "Company Directory"

A more rigorous task. A visual plan of the structure for the application was required prior to any development. This was also developed as a 'mobile first' application. The application is used to maintain the company MySQL personnel database with CRUD modules. Final sign-off is only granted after a trainee supplies an independent user's testified report on the application, providing confirmation of the system's ability to perform error-free.

CAREER HISTORY:

Aug 2022 – Present POSITION HELD:

National Grid Cyber Technical Assistant

- Supported the Cyber Optel Manager with administration of Cyber operations
- Supported the Cyber Portfolio Leads with financial administration tasks
- Requisitioned and receipted purchase orders
- Booked deliveries, site surveys, coordination meetings and installation works
- Attended planning, coordination, and financial review meetings
- Developed a procedure for the team, to simplify the process of managing Purchase Orders and recording financial transactions, to facilitate ready access to financial data and both timely and accurate financial reporting

Oct 2019 – Feb 2021 POSITION HELD:

Hamitaf Ltd Virtual Data Administrator

- Offered freelance online data administrative services
- Data analysis with Excel
- Collated business performance data from various sources
- Data processing and report generation
- Spreadsheet creation and maintenance of databases
- General administration (data entry, word processing, email inbox management)
- Completed Project Management and Advanced Excel courses in this period

Apr 2016 – Aug 2018 POSITION HELD:

Rethink Mental Illness Administrator

- Compiled and collated statistical data on the Service's activities, performed analysis on the data, updated relevant databases and generated monthly and annual reports
- Supported the Service Manager, Head of Service, and a team of Advisers with administrative and financial management tasks
- Initiated and responded to client communication. Ensured a high quality and prompt response to all enquiries
- Trained new team members on how to use certain systems in the Service
- Revamped the Information Reviewers Excel database, and the method of storing information in it, reducing the time taken for selection of information reviewers from the database, by about 75%

May 1998 – Sep 2014 POSITION HELD:

University of Lagos Assistant Chief Systems Analyst

- Developed in-house database management software
- Created and maintained databases, ensuring the integrity of their content
- Managed a data processing department: digitally processed semester examinations, staff training tests and some entrance examination results.
 Ensured jobs were processed accurately and within timescales. Utilised high level of attention to detail

- Supervised daily operations and handled the finances. Purchased all office supplies and maintained all office resources, liaised with suppliers and maintenance personnel, both external and internal
- Managed team of data processing staff. Catered for their welfare and progression
- Provided administrative and IT support to other teams and colleagues at different levels. Liaised with staff in other departments across the University
- Simplified administrative processes with software solutions, creating ease of work and reduced task-completion times by up to 50%

VOLUNTEER WORK:

Sep 2014 – Oct 2015 POSITION HELD:

DWP/EFA Foundation/Green Lane Community Centre

Administration/Customer Service

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019 Jul 1992 - Nov 1997 Jan 1989 - Jul 1992 Aug 1987 - Aug 1988 **Customer Service Officer**

Senior Programmer/Part-time Lecturer/Mathematics Tutor

Lecturer III (Mathematics)
Youth Corp member

EDUCATION & TRAINING:

2021 The Linux Professional Institute with CISCO Network Academy

Certified in Linux Essentials

2021 The Python Institute with CISCO Network Academy

Certified Associate Python Programmer

2021 Insight Edge

Excel for Data Analysis

2020 Corporate Finance Institute

Excel Crash Course Certificate

2019 365 Careers

Beginner Project Management Certificate

2018 – 2019 Birmingham City University

Postgraduate Certificate in Educational Studies

2018 Rethink Mental Illness L&D Service

Customer Service Essentials

2015 Learndirect

ECDL IT Skills & Improving Productivity Level 2

2009 – 2010 National Institute for Information Technology

Certified Enterprise Application Developer & Solutions Architect on Sun Java

1993 – 1995 Abubakar Tafawa Balewa University

MSc Computer Science

1983 – 1987 Ahmadu Bello University

BSc Maths with Computer Science

1982 – 1983 IJMB

Three A-Levels

1977 – 1982 GCE/GCSE

Eight O-Levels

HOBBIES & EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Reading, Analytical Puzzles, Digital games, Language learning (Digital and Human), Baking, Wool craft, Sewing